# **Gopal Kumar**

Jaipur, RJ 302020 | +917988179811 | gopalkumarss0786@gmail.com

# **Professional Summary**

Forward-thinking Executive (Remote Sensing & GIS) with proven record of accomplishment in GIS Industries during 4-years career. Driven ambitious change manager dedicated to continuous business improvement focused on enhancing revenue and streamlining business operations. Diligent in driving profit maximization through multifaced approaches.

### Skills

- Creation of Digital Database
- Base map
- Land use and Land cover
- Digitization skills
- Communications
- Information consolidation
- Raw point cloud P2 data processing
- Terra Match (P2 and ALS data)

- Arc GIS
- Bentley Microstation
- Quantum GIS
- Global Mapper
- Hx Map
- Rhino
- Use of Google Earth

# Work History

## **Executive** (Remote Sensing & GIS)

Genesys International Corporation Ltd- Jaipur, Rajasthan

07/2018 to Current

## Activities:-

- P2 (Pegasus 2) Raw data Processing (IE & Auto P)
- Lidar data classification using Microstation.
- LIDAR Data adjustment (Terra matching of Pegasus 2 & ALS Data)
- Creation of 3D building models with the help of 2D data by using Rhino and HxMap Software.
- Creation of base map (2D) features by using QGIS.

I am also working in a Carmera Process mapping data captured for autonomous vehicles where I am preparing the following products using mobile LIDAR survey data:

- Base features (Road margins, Center median, intersection lines, junction cores, carriageways, crossing zones, delay aprons, road segments, parking areas).
- Overlay features (Lane lines, delay lines, parking lines, restricted zones, dash marking, traffic arrows, parking zones).
- Behavioral features (Lanes, connection paths, lane connectors).
- All features are capturing in Bentley Micro station.

03/2018 to 06/2018

AutoCAD Engineer DIN Engineering Services (Client:-USA Govt.).

**Project Name:-USA Solar Project** 

#### **Activities:**

- Data Extraction from satellite images.
- Digitization of the solar panel area and creating the digital database of the particular AOI.

AutoCAD Operator
RamTech software solutions Pvt. Ltd
(Client:-Maharashtra Govt.)

09/2017 to 03/2018

Project\_Name:-National Land Records Modernization Programme (NLRMP)

#### **Activities:**

- Georeference map sheets and satellite images.
- LULC and creation of the digital database of the AOI.
- Quality checking of the data.

GIS Engineer (Remote Sensing & GIS)
Shivom Engineers Associates Pvt. Ltd.
(Client: Gujrat Govt.)

06/2016to 09/2017

Project Name:-DILRMP (Digital India Land Record Modernization Programme)

## **Activities:**

- Georeference map sheets and satellite images
- Digitization of the khasra Maps and creation of the digital database of the AOI.
- Quality checking of the data.

## Education

Diploma in Architecture Assistantship from Govt. Polytechnic Ambala City.

# Strength

- Decision making
- Problem solving
- Productivity
- Multitasking

## **Additional Information**

- Interest: Internet Surfing, Reading Books, Driving, Sketching
- Languages: Can read, write and speak English, Hindi, Punjabi and Dongri fluently.

## Declaration

I declare that the foregoing information is correct and complete to the best of my knowledge and belief and nothing has been concealed / distorted. If at any time, I am found to have concealed / distorted any material information; my appointment shall be liable to summary rejected.

Place: Jaipur (GOPAL KUMAR)